<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blender | on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1337/tags/blender-/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blender | on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 04:48:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1337/tags/blender-/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Emission Volumetrics and volume shaders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/9_emission_volumetrics_shaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 04:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/9_emission_volumetrics_shaders/</guid>
      <description>These are two closely related shaders that go well with each other. Lets start with the emission. It makes an object glow with a particular colour. This is useful when the lighting used in a scene is shaped a particular way(like those halo lights streamers use). This gives the scene the specific look imagined.&#xA;If you’ve seen a rendered image and something made it look ethereal or punchy, its probably the emission shader.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freaky Wireframes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/8_freaky_wireframes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 04:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/8_freaky_wireframes/</guid>
      <description>Let’s talk about the wireframe modifier. Looks like just another boring modifier but honestly one of the more powerful modifiers available.&#xA;It takes a solid object and converts it into another solid mesh with the original object’s edges. The more you difficult the merrier.&#xA;The offset value determines if the mesh appears inside or outside the original object, essentially allowing you to create cool effects with a duplicated object along with the original.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Select stuff the lazy way (in edit mode)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/2_blender_lazy_select/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/2_blender_lazy_select/</guid>
      <description>The most annoying thing i had to do in blender was selecting every single edge or corner by myself. Not a hard thing when wwhat you’re designing is small but when its got like 4 subdivision modifiers stuff becomes hard.&#xA;So, to select rows of edges or corners that are not even linked but are on the same line, use ctrl + alt + left click&#xA;To select alternates from anything you’ve got selected go to the select panel and click checker deselct</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
