<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 06:48:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1337/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Functional Programming with Elixir</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/12_functional_programming_with_elixir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 06:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/12_functional_programming_with_elixir/</guid>
      <description>During my time as a professional software developer, I have always been working with object oriented languages and all codebases I have interacted with have been written with the object oriented paradigm. So when I came across the functional programming paradigm, I got curious to learn more. Reading about Haskell and Clojure portrayed functional languages as hard to grasp and not very useful. But I found out about elixir and the syntax looked promising.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blind Watchmaker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/11_the_blind_watchmaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 06:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/11_the_blind_watchmaker/</guid>
      <description>Genome Dynamics Visualization App: Description: During my Undergraduate years, I got introduced to the concept of The Blind Watchmaker by Richard Dawkins. The concept intrigued me a lot, and I got the chance to recreate and visualize the concept with the help of programming. The Program lets the user interact with a set of organisms and select the winning organism each generation, and the subsequent organisms will evolve the desired organ with superior functionality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with cloud systems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/10_cloud_systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 04:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/10_cloud_systems/</guid>
      <description>Learning system design with #crio.do&#xA;I have refrained from understanding how cloud computing works, for fear of being overwhelmed by the AWS beginner guide. But I got a chance to understand it from a different source. Heres what I learnt from the system design miro experience.&#xA;SETTING UP The first step in designing is to rent a virtual machine from Amazon Web Services. Create a new AWS account and head to the launch EC2 instance page.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emission Volumetrics and volume shaders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/9_emission_volumetrics_shaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 04:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/9_emission_volumetrics_shaders/</guid>
      <description>These are two closely related shaders that go well with each other. Lets start with the emission. It makes an object glow with a particular colour. This is useful when the lighting used in a scene is shaped a particular way(like those halo lights streamers use). This gives the scene the specific look imagined.&#xA;If you’ve seen a rendered image and something made it look ethereal or punchy, its probably the emission shader.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freaky Wireframes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/8_freaky_wireframes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 04:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/8_freaky_wireframes/</guid>
      <description>Let’s talk about the wireframe modifier. Looks like just another boring modifier but honestly one of the more powerful modifiers available.&#xA;It takes a solid object and converts it into another solid mesh with the original object’s edges. The more you difficult the merrier.&#xA;The offset value determines if the mesh appears inside or outside the original object, essentially allowing you to create cool effects with a duplicated object along with the original.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bellman, Markov and the Q</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/7_1_bellman_markov_q/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 03:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/7_1_bellman_markov_q/</guid>
      <description>Surfing through some hackerrank profiles, I found a guy, who made an AI chess addon that can view any chess board in a browsre page and provide a continuation for it. Which got me really interested in AI and spending money on udemy.&#xA;The concept that was the base of all the AI magic was the bellman’s equation.&#xA;It describes that the value of any state of an environment as the maximum sum of reward for performing an action and the value of the next state.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Domain System</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/7_domain_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 03:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/7_domain_system/</guid>
      <description>The domain name system, DNS for short is one of those creative ideas that make human life easier on the internet. The system is for converting human understandable domain names into ip addresses for easy relembrance and searching of a particular ip address.&#xA;There are four important parts for a smooth domain retrieval. They are the recursive DNS retriever, the Top Level Domain nameserver, root nameserver and authoritative nameserver.&#xA;The recuesive retriever is the first one to recieve the user input ‘theserver.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacuums and tubes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/6_vaccuums_and_tubes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 03:34:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/6_vaccuums_and_tubes/</guid>
      <description>Disassembling an old tape recorder, I found there were tiny bulb structures that didn’t seem to light up (or have tungsten for that matter). Upon research I was surprised to find that there was a time in history where silicon was just sand.&#xA;This was the period of vaccum tubes. This is a creative engineering solution for computing problems.&#xA;The tube consists of two electrodes(as usual) the cathode and anode. The cathode is heated which produces electrons due to a phenomenon called thermionic emission.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem with Binary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/5_problem_with_binary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 06:47:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/5_problem_with_binary/</guid>
      <description>Confusion arose when the lights turned on when they were supposed to be off and lit the room blue.&#xA;The LED was connected to pin 18 of the gpio and given an on pulse. But nothing interesting happened. When the off signal was given, the LED started off.&#xA;Upon investigating the problem in the strange waters of the internet, there were a lot of confusing answers and I realized the fact that a basic understanding of how LEDs and gpio works was essential.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem with Binary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/4_1_internet_protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 06:47:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/4_1_internet_protocols/</guid>
      <description>Therw are two protocols for internet traffic.&#xA;TCP(transmission control protocol) is the safe and secure protocol. It engages a three way handshake with the recipient. The first phase is the SYN(chronous) where it establishes and verifies connection with the neighbour. The second phase is the SYN ack(synchronous acknowledgement) where the recipient computer ensures connection. The third phase is acknowledgement when the sender computer acknowledges the SYN ack and starts sending data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blindfold and Perms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/4_blindfold_perms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 06:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/4_blindfold_perms/</guid>
      <description>Solving the Rubik’s cube sub-one minute is cool, solving it sub five is probably overkill. But solving it blindfolded is a whole another story. It isn’t hard or anything until you reach the world of parity. Let’s get some basics straight&#xA;Lets forget orientation for this one and focus on permutation. From the permutation groups field in mathematics, the edges and corners of a rubiks cube can only be shuffled around in odd numbered groups(excluding one, because you can’t switch a single piece, duh).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hard Not Tough</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/3_hard_not_tough/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/3_hard_not_tough/</guid>
      <description>I was always confident that diamonds can be broken with a hammer. But my world was shattered when a guy hit a diamond with a hammer and it made a dent on the anvil. A few seconds later the same guy broke it with a comparitively powerless hit. There was definitely something shiny here.&#xA;To understand what was going on I had to understand the difference between hardness and toughness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Select stuff the lazy way (in edit mode)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/2_blender_lazy_select/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/2_blender_lazy_select/</guid>
      <description>The most annoying thing i had to do in blender was selecting every single edge or corner by myself. Not a hard thing when wwhat you’re designing is small but when its got like 4 subdivision modifiers stuff becomes hard.&#xA;So, to select rows of edges or corners that are not even linked but are on the same line, use ctrl + alt + left click&#xA;To select alternates from anything you’ve got selected go to the select panel and click checker deselct</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stuff That Leaves Forever</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1337/blog/1_beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1337/blog/1_beginning/</guid>
      <description>There are certain things that will always come back to haunt you for forgetting them.Such things are quite interesting and are from too niche of a field to be found with a simple search. it seems there are things to be found out everyday. so this is a collection of what I have loved and left my mind blown. Mostly engineering breakthroughs or a creative way to edit stuff in blender and some shortcuts for editing software.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
